Guide to the Records of the Working Group at Park West Village TAM.780
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Records of the Working Group at Park West Village
2011-2017
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Armstrong, Winifred
Working Group at Park West Village
TAM.780
2.48 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in shared housing.
57.53 Megabytes in 25 computer files.
Park West Village (PWV) was developed in the late-1950s and early-1960s as part of a government-subsidized urban redevelopment project on Manhattan's Upper West Side; located between 97th to 100th streets, Central Park West, and Columbus Avenue. The Working Group at Park West Village began in 2009 to define and represent the community's interests. Records of the Working Group at Park West Village (2011-2017) consist of legal documents on paper and electronic files that offer insight to the Park West Village community's opposition to the Jewish Home and Hospital for the Aged, operated by the New Jewish Home, on proposing construction of a twenty-story nursing home on the Upper West Side of New York City. The records consist primarily of expert, political, and community testimonies, preliminary and final reports of the New York State Department of Health Environment Impact Studies (FEIS), which the Working Group forced by uncovering and sourcing toxins, and traces of lead in the proposed building space. The records also include letters and signatures of protest addressed to the New York State Department of Health from members of the Park West Village community, parents, faculty, and other members of Public School 163 (P.S. 163) who shared their concerns about the dangers of exposing students to lead. The materials also contain court transcripts, affidavits, documents on open space and zoning issues raised by the Working Group at the New York City Board of Standards and Appeals, and the legal judgments that followed.
Scope and Contents
Records of the Working Group at Park West Village (2011-2017) consist of legal documents on paper and electronic files that offer insight to the Park West Village community's opposition to the Jewish Home and Hospital for the Aged, operated by the New Jewish Home, on proposing construction of a twenty-story nursing home on the Upper West Side of New York City. The records consist primarily of expert, political, and community public comments and testimonies, preliminary and final reports of the New York State Department of Health Environment Impact Studies, which the Working Group forced by uncovering and sourcing toxins, and traces of lead in the proposed building space. The records also include letters and petitions of protest addressed to the New York State Department of Health from members of the Park West Village community, parents, faculty, and other members of Public School 163 (P.S. 163) who shared their concerns about the dangers of exposing students to lead. The materials also contain court transcripts, affidavits, documents on open space and zoning issues raised by the Working Group at the New York City Board of Standards and Appeals, and the legal judgments that followed.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical Note
Park West Village (PWV) was developed in the late-1950s and early-1960s as part of a government-subsidized urban redevelopment project on Manhattan's Upper West Side; located between 97th to 100th streets, Central Park West, and Columbus Avenue. The PWV includes approximately five-thousand resident condominium owners, rent stabilized, and market rate tenants. The Working Group at Park West Village began in 2009 to define and represent the community's interests against the proposals and development of the Jewish Home and Hospital for the Aged on West 100th street.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Win Armstrong in February 2019. The accession number associated with this gift is 2019.046.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted. An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Testimonies.; Correspondence.; Briefs (legal documents); Upper West Side (New York, N.Y.); Public health -- United States.; Transcripts.; Housing and health; Lead poisoning -- New York (N.Y.); Armstrong, Winifred; New York (State). Department of Health; Jewish Home and Hospital for Aged (New York, N.Y.)
- Newspaper Clipping, 2016 (Box Shared Tamiment 066, Folder 2)
- Open Letter From Stakeholders of the Park West Village Neighborhood, 2011-02-07 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Signed Petition to Governor Cuomo, 2013-06-06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- New York State Department of Health: Preliminary Environmental Assessment, June 2013
  - Digital Files, TW_TAM_780_ER_2
  - Paper Files (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Scoping Meeting Documents, 2013-07 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Public Comments: Residents on DEIS Scoping Document, September-October 2013
  - Digital Files, TW_TAM_780_ER_1
  - Paper Files (Box 1, Folder 5-6, Box 2, Folder 3, Box 3)
- Letters to Governor Cuomo and New York State Health Commissioner Shah, 2013-06-2013-07 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Public Comments: Public School 163 on DEIS Scoping Document, 2013-10-04 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- New York State Department of Health: State Environmental Quality Review - Final Scoping Document, 2014-01-28 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Public Comments: Park West Village Tenants Association, 2013-10-02 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- New York State Department of Health: Draft Environmental Impact Statement (DEIS), 2013-03-21 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Draft of Environmental Impact Statement Hearing Transcript, 2014-05-07 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Public Comments: Residents on the Draft Environmental Impact Statement, 2014-05 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- New York State Department of Health: Final Environmental Impact Statement, 2014-11-14 (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
- Environmental Law Case Files: Proceedings, 2015 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
- Article 78 Petition - Filing Documents, 2015-04-10 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  File includes material resticted by attorney-client privilege.
- Article 78 Petition - Reply Briefs, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Article 78 Petition - Brief for Friends of P.S. 163, 2017-08 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Board of Standards and Appeals Hearing Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New York City Department of Buildings: Zoning Resolution, 2012-08-31 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Zoning Lot Data, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Zoning Memos and Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- 808 Columbus Materials, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Open Letter to Department of Building Commissioner Rick Chandler, 2014-08-22 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Text Amendment to Zoning Resolution, 2015-02-02 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- New York City Board of Standards and Appeals: Forms and Regulations, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: Board of Standards and Appeals, 2014-12 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Appeal Filed with New York City Board of Standards and Appeals, 2014-12 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- New York City Board of Standards and Appeals: Response to Notice of Comments, 2015-03-05 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- BSA Appeal Post-Hearing Documents, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Kramer Levin to New York City Board of Standards and Appeals, 2015-03-19 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- NYC Department of Buildings to Board of Standards and Appeals, 2015-03-31 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Peyton Rebuttal to New York City Board of Standards and Appeals, 2015-04-08 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Peyton Rebuttal to Kramer Levin, 2015-04-06 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- New York Board of Standards and Appeals Hearing Notes, 2015-04-14 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Letters of Support Submitted at Hearing, 2015-04-14 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Letters of Opposition Submitted at Hearing, 2015-04-15 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Post-hearing Memorandum, 2015-05-13 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- New York City Department of Buildings Response to Board of Standards and Appeals, 2015-05-28 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Kramer Levin Submission to Board of Standards and Appeals, 2015-05-28 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Peyton Rebuttal to Kramer Levin, 2015-06-04 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Draft Outline for Continuation Hearing, 2015-06-23 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Post-hearing Letters of Support, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Appeals Hearing Summary of Argument, 2015-07-29 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Public Comments and Correspondences, 2013-2014 (Box 4, Folder 29)